## MARK ELLIOTT

Mechanicsville, VA

Phone: 804 746-8288 | Email: markelliottva@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/markelliottva/ | GitHub: https://github.com/melliott7264

| Portfolio: https://melliott7264.github.io/react-portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in Information Technology working with clients at all levels of the organization to ascertain client needs and create appropriate technical solutions. Functioned as a web developer in support of various personal and self-employment business endeavors for over 10 years mostly on a WordPress platform using HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and MySQL to create and customize websites. Completed a 24 week Coding Bootcamp at the University of Richmond to enhance skills as a fullstack developer including the successful deployment of several collaborative coding projects. Continuing to pursue personal web development projects. Reliable and organized with excellent verbal and written communication skills. A self-starter with a track record of being a team leader, solving complex problems, and doing what is necessary to get the job done. A persistent and patient problem solver. Always learning.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Jquery Jquery UI Bootstrap Bulma Moment.js Day.js Node.js Bcrypt Express Express-Sessions SQL Sequelize Handlebars Mongoose React JSONWebToken and GraphQL

Applications: WordPress, Elementor, Yoast, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, MySQL, MySQL Workbench, PhpMyAdmin, MongoDB, Apache, Local by Flywheel, AWS Lightsail, AWS S3, cPanel, Filezilla, VS Code, Git, GitHub, MacOS, Linux, Windows, Google Apps, MS Word, MS Excel, Adobe Lightroom, and Adobe Photoshop

### **PROJECTS**

## Personal Website | https://www.markelliottva.com/

- This is a solo project to redesign Mark Elliott's personal website to share his traditional art and crafts work.
- Developed in WordPress using a custom theme with a landing page carousel written from scratch using jQuery.

## Muzzleloader Range Log | https://muzzleloader-range-log.herokuapp.com/

- This is a solo project to create a MERN application to produce a range log tailored toward the needs of serious shooters of traditional muzzleloading firearms.
- Developed in Mongo/Mongoose, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, JSONWebToken, React, and Bootstrap.

## Money Matters | https://still-sea-70396.herokuapp.com/

- Part of a four person team to create a MERN application to produce an economics and finance news discussion site. Mark produced the server template and most of the Mongoose and GraphQL work as well as the React for the article comments.
- Developed in Mongo/Mongoose, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, JSONWebToken, React, and Bootstrap.

#### EXPERIENCE

# **Teaching Assistant** 2022 – Present edX, Remote

Support Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp students during class and office hours. Guide and encourage students' in-class activities as well as their offline work, challenges, and projects. Grade projects and support the instructor with class management tasks.

## Web Developer 2019 – Present

## Central Virginia Intergroup of Overeaters Anonymous, Richmond, VA

Work with leadership on a volunteer basis to translate the organization mission to reach those suffering from eating disorders into information technology solutions serving the community of Overeater Anonymous members in the Central Virginia region. *Kev Accomplishments:* 

- Design, create, and maintain the Intergroup's website: <a href="https://www.centralvaoa.org">https://www.centralvaoa.org</a>
- Support internal e-mail communication using MailChimp
- Used WordPress, Google Analytics, HTML, and CSS to create and maintain the site,

## **Proprietor/Web Developer** 2010 – 2022

## Mark Elliott Crafts (Self-employed), Mechanicsville, VA

Created traditional crafts serving those collectors, reenactors, and sportsmen with an interest in American history and longrifle culture. Also worked as a photographer specializing in product and virtual reality photography. Used technology as a primary means to market Mark Elliott's unique crafts and photography work mostly on a bespoke basis. Nearly all revenue came through the web presence.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Crafts work and and photography repeatedly recognized for excellence
- Designed, created, and maintained several websites over the years serving Mark Elliott's various business interests: <a href="https://www.markelliottva.com">https://www.markelliottva.com</a>
- Provided all the photography and graphics for the websites
- Used WordPress, Elementor, Yoast, Google Analytics, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, PhpMyAdmin, Adobe Lightroom, and Adobe Photoshop to create and maintain the websites over the years

#### EDUCATION

## Boot Camp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS with GraphQL.

## B.S. Information Systems: Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA